London calling,with Frenchmen speaking to their countrymen.
在伦敦呼叫法国同胞们
Take a look at that. What a handsome sight...
你看,德意志帝国的骄傲…
...the pride of the Third Reich.
多帅啊
The brave sergeant taking coffee to the beachgunners.
勇敢的中士送咖啡 给在海边的狙击手喝
So that's a sample of the master race. In a pig's eye.
在猪猡的眼中 这是最优秀的种族的模范
What's going on here?
怎么了?
(Tr.V.P.I.B.)
(碉堡部总指挥部)
In this darkest hour, in the gloom of night...
在这黑暗的时刻 在这黑暗的深夜…
...we must not despair.
我们绝不容许感到绝望
Let us keep our faith intact, unswerving!
(路易斯鲁兰神父)
For each of us...
因为我们每个人…
...deliverance is coming.
就快从这场战争中解放了
We need mines and obstacles along the whole coast.
我们必须沿着整片海滩…
At every beach,on every dune...
布下地雷和…
...on every rock.
障碍物
How many have been installed?
已经设置了多少?
Four million,Herr Field Marshal.
四百万,将军
It has to be six million by May.
(战地司令官,B军团) (艾文隆美尔)
There's no point in even discussing rest.
这项工作 让我们的部队精疲力尽
...which would your troops rather be...
你的军队宁愿选择精疲力尽…
...exhausted or dead?
还是死亡?
Just look at it,gentlemen.
各位,看看这个地方
How calm,how peaceful it is.
这么的安静,祥和
A strip of water between England and the Continent...
隔海的对岸就是英国…
...between the Allies and us.
把我们和盟军相隔
But beyond that peaceful horizon, a monster waits.
但是在这片安详的地平线远方 有只怪兽在等着我们
A coiled spring of men, ships and planes...
有一大群的军队军舰,和飞机…
...straining to be released against us.
用尽一切方法想打败我们
But not a single Allied soldier shall reach the shore.
不过盟军休想踏上这个海岸一步
Not a single Anglo-American shall set foot on the beaches.
没有任何美国人可以涉足海滩
Whenever or wherever this invasion may come,gentlemen...
不管何时何地 只要他们敢妄动…
...I shall destroy the enemy there, at the water's edge.
我就会在这海岸的一隅 将他们摧毁!
Believe me,gentlemen.
相信我,各位
The first 24 hours of the invasion will be decisive.
攻击最初的24小时最具关键性
For the Allies as well as the Germans, it will be the longest day...
对盟军和我们德军来说 都会是最长的一日…
...the longest day.
最长的一日!
-The poem by Verlaine? -Yes,the first verse.
-法国诗人魏伦的诗? -对,第一节
Play it back!
再放一次!
Silence!
安静!
Frenchmen speaking to their countrymen.
呼叫法国同胞
Here are some personal messages.
这是私人讯息
"The long sobs of the violins of autumn. "
“秋天小提琴的低泣”
I repeat:
我重复:
Have you notified all commands?
你通知了所有的军团了吗?
If Berlin is right, when we intercept the second verse...
如果柏林方面估计的没错 当我们读到第二节的时候…
...it will mean the invasion will come within 24 hours.
表示对方攻击会在24小时内展开
Give me the text of the second verse.
把第二节拿给我看
"Wounds my heart with a monotonous languor."
“用单调的沉闷伤害我的心”
We've intercepted hundreds of messages in the last year,hundreds!
去年我们已经看了 上百段的诗句了,上百段!
I've ordered alerts again and again.
我重复下达了紧急待命的通知
Why should this poem mean more than other messages?
为什么这本诗 比其它的诗还要重要?
Tell me this:
告诉我:
Does it give us any clue as to where they will land and when?
难道它会告诉我们 对方何时会在何处上岸吗?
Of course it doesn't.
当然不会
I have half a million men under my command.
我有五十万大军让我指挥
How can I maintain discipline if I keep my troops on the alert...
我怎么同时让我的军队备战 跟维持军纪呢?
...just because a pair of nitwits in Berlin intercept a poem?
就为了柏林方面的一堆傻子 所解读的诗句?
No,Blumentritt,no alert.
不,布鲁门特里特 不用备战
And especially not in this weather.
尤其不用在这种天气之下
-Anything else? -No,sir.
-还有事吗? -没有,长官
Good morning,field marshal.
早安,将军
-Any news? -Nothing important.
-有消息吗? -没什么重要的
Fighter bombers hit the Pas-de- Calais yesterday afternoon.
昨天下午帕德加雷被轰炸了
Nothing much happened last night. The storm.
昨晚有风暴所以没什么事情发生
That's all I'm interested in this morning,the storm.
我今天早上最关心的就是风暴了
It came from nowhere, blew my roses to bits.
不知道会从哪吹来 把我的玫瑰都吹坏了
There are 5-foot waves in the Channel...
海峡上的浪有5尺高…
...and winds of 30 to 40 miles per hour.
风速每小时是30-40里
For the month of June...
这种六月天…
...it's the worst Channel storm in 20 years.
真是20年来最糟的天气
My appointment at Berchtesgaden?
到元帅那开会?
General JodI will see the F¨¹hrer today...
朱铎将军今日要去见元帅…
...and confirm the appointment for you.
您的行程也确认了
Will you still go to Germany as planned?
你还是要按计划去德国吗?
Can you think of a better time?
还有更好的时间吗?
The weather is expected to continue like this for another week.
这样的天气 可能还要持续一周
Snap it up. Jerk the lead.
快,把盘子拿好
You expect us to eat this slop again?
又要我们吃这种东西?
I don't care what you do with it,mac.
我才不管你吃不吃
Eat it,throw it out.
快吃,不然就丢掉
I get paid for cooking it.
我只是拿薪水做事
Come on. Put it on.
快给我吧
Snap it up.
快点
Jerk the lead.
把盘子拿好
Didn't you get any sleep?
没睡吗?
Are you kidding? I haven't slept since we got here.
开什么玩笑 我从来到这儿就没睡过了
I got the absolute lowdown.
我得到确切情报
It's on for tonight. For sure.
今晚就要发动攻击,准没错
Yeah.
少吹了
I got in this crap game with this guy from F Company.
昨晚我和一个将军侍卫 玩骰子的时候听来的
-He's an orderly for some general. -Move it. Move it.
-他是某个将军的随从 -快一点,快
Hey,Hutchy!
嘿,哈奇!
Hutchy,I want to ask you something.
哈奇,我有事情要问你
Hey,Hutchinson...
嘿,哈奇森…
...do you think they'd let me write home? If it was really important?
要是真的很重要 你想他们会让我写信回家吗?
Not likely,mate. Security.
不太可能,保密的关系
I don't think old Churchill trusts us.
邱吉尔可能不会相信我们
It's the wife,you see. She's going to have a baby.
我是要写给我太太 她快生了
Your first,is it?
你的老大,对吗?
Oh,it's not mine,but I'm dead worried about her.
不是我的小孩 不过我非常担心她
She's not too strong,you see.
她不是很坚强
Man,that stink.
臭死了
Diesel oil,backed-up toilets,vomit.
柴油味,厕所也坏了,还有呕吐物
And there ain't no place left to get sick in.
让病人休息的地方都没有
The puke bags is full.
呕吐袋全都满了
The fire buckets is full.
连火药桶都吐满了
All we got left is our helmets.
只剩钢盔了
June.
六月…
Every June my old man used to take me camping...
每到六月,我父亲就会带我到…
...up in the Blue Mountains.
蓝山上露营
We'd hunt and fish all day long.
我们一整天 都在那儿打猎钓鱼
And at night...
到了晚上…
...we'd sleep out under the stars.
就睡在星空下
Didn't even need a blanket.
连毯子都不需要
June.
真怀念六月啊
Wind and rain. Wind and rain.
风雨啊,风雨啊
Don't it ever stop?
何时才会停?
Look,Dad,all I want to do is get going.
听好,爸爸,我只想赶快上路
Wind or no wind. Even if we land in Paris on the Eiffel Tower.
管他风雨交加 或是我们降落在艾菲尔铁塔上
-Come to think of it-- -Colonel wants us.
-现在想想… -上校要集合所有的人
All of us.
所有的人
I've notified the adjutant, change in schedule.
(班杰明凡德沃特上校) (第82空降师)
After briefing session today...
计划改变了,开完会之后 今天所有的部队…
...all troops will participate in ground tactics and deployment.
都要加入地面作战
In this weather,sir?
在这种天气作战吗?长官
Of course,Harding,if you can ensure that we'll land in France...
除非你能保证我们可以…
-...in sunshine and dry weather. -Didn't mean that.
-在大太阳底下登陆法国 -我不是这个意思
-What did you mean? -It isn't the weather.
-那是什么意思? -问题不是天气
It's the waiting. These men are itching to go.
而是要等多久 士兵们都不耐烦了
I don't think I have to remind you...
你要知道…
...that this war has been going on for almost five years.
这场战几乎已经打了五年了
Half of Europe has been overrun and occupied.
欧洲超过一半的地方都被占领了
We're comparative newcomers.
我们还算是新加入战局的
England's gone through a blitz with a knife at her throat since 1940.
英国自1940年起就受到攻击…
I am quite sure that they too are impatient and itching to go.
我确定他们也迫不及待要进攻
Do I make myself clear?
说得够清楚了吗?
Yes,sir. Quite clear.
是,很清楚
Three million men penned up on this island.
三百万大军被困在这个岛上
All over England, in staging areas like this.
遍布全英国像这样的地方
We're on the threshold of the most crucial day of our times.
本世纪 最关键的一刻就要展开
Three million men out there...
三百万秣马厉兵…
...keyed up,and waiting for that big step-off.
就等攻击声响起
They aren't exactly alone.
不只是只有我们而已
Notify the men. Full packs and equipment,1400 hours.
全体注意 下午两点备齐所有装备
Yes,sir.
是,长官
They said they have both issues available.
他们说两方面的消息都有
I prefer this type. It allows you more freedom.
我个人比较喜欢这样子 多一点自由
Quicker to get rid of when we hit the beach.
上岸后,丢掉不用的装备
-Well? -It's on.
-怎样? -开始了
Tonight,as scheduled.
今晚就要照预定计划进行
-If the weather isn't worse. -How worse can it get?
-只要天气不变坏的话 -还能再更坏吗?
Ike has called a high-level conference for 9:30.
艾森豪九点半要开上层会议
I am not Eisenhower. I am an assistant division commander.
反正我也不是艾森豪 我只是助理指挥官
I don't know from nothing, but he can't call it off again.
反正我不管 只要不再延后就可以了
Frank,turn that thing off.
法兰克,把它关掉
Four thousand ships loaded for bear.
四千艘船已整装备妥
Troops ready to go.
部队准备就绪
Eleven thousand planes on the line.
还有一万一千架飞机
Eighteen thousand paratroopers. God only knows how many gliders.
一万八千名伞兵 更有数不清的滑翔翼待命
Norm,relax.
诺曼,轻松一点
RAF says the gale can stop as suddenly as it began.
皇家空军说强风随时会停
So they told us yesterday and the day before.
他们前二天也是这么说
Look,Norm.
听好,诺曼
We're all of us just as...
我们也和你们一样…
...dedicated to this thing as you are, just as anxious to get going.
急着开始进攻
And that includes Ike.
包括艾森豪在内
Now if he calls it off again, he knows what he's doing.
如果他再叫停 他应该道自己在做什么
Of course he does. I know that.
他当然知道
I'm just thinking about those assault troops. 200,000 of them...
我只是在想着那些二十万名 在海上漂流的突击部队…
...out there on those ships. They're probably seasick as hell.
可能会吐翻了
Some of those men have been on those tubs for almost three days.
你知道有人已经在船上 待了三天吗?
I say go.
我觉得不要拖延了
Go. Weather or no weather.
赶快进攻,管它什么天气
No!
不!
A hundred on the bone! Let's go.
骰子游戏开始了
-Hey,give me 50 bucks. I'm busted. -I'm not doing so good myself.
-给我50块,我没钱了 -我自己的运气也背
Hey,lend me 50 bucks?
借我50块吧
-Lend me 20 bucks? -Drop dead.
-借我20块? -去死吧
Lend me 10?
借我10块?
-Fifty on a bet. -I got it.
-一注50块 -我有
One,two,three,four,five.
一,二,三,四,五
Fifty!
五十!
Let me hear it,let me hear it.
一定要中…
-Five and two,four and three. -Six! That's the way we go!
-五二和四三 -六,太好了
Seven points in a row. It ain't logical,it just ain't logical.
连赢7手,真邪门
-There's 100 out there. -A hundred dollars,$20.
-总共100块 -100块还有20块
Anything open?
还有空位吗?
-Forty more.
-还要四十块
You got a bet.
下吧
-Okay,you mother-loving-- -Just a minute. Wait a minute.
-好,你这王八… -等一下
Here you are. Use this.
拿去,用这个
-You don't think I'd-- -I don't think anything.
-你不会以为我要… -我不是都不以为
I just like to hear the sound when it comes out of the cup.
我只是想听它发出的声音
That's it. Shake it.
就是这样,用力摇吧
Okay. Let me see what you do with it now. Go ahead. Shoot.
让我看看你的手气 开吧
-What is it? -Nothing.
-是什么? -什么都不是
-Seven! -That's what I wanted!
-七! -太棒了
Who put this cup in the game?
不想想看杯子是谁的主意?
-Next shooter. Who's coming up? -I'll go $ 100.
-下一个轮到谁? -我下100块
He's shooting 100. Who's got it?
好,他下100 还有谁?谁要下?
-Watch your side bets. -A hundred dollars.
-插花的注意了 -100块
You got a letter for me. Schultz,huh?
有我的信吗?对,舒兹
Yeah,that's it.
太好了,就这样
Thanks,buddy.
谢啦
-How much did you take him for? -Not much. Just a hair over 2500.
-你赢了多少? -不多,两千五百多块而已
-Twenty-five hundred? -Yeah.
-两千五百? -对
Oh,man,2500?
天啊,两千五百?
It's too bad you had to win it now.
你现在赢实在不巧
What do you mean,now?
什么意思?
Suppose we take off tonight. What will you do with it?
要是我们今晚得出击呢? 钱要怎么办?
Five I take with me to Paris to blow on the broads and wine.
我要拿500块去巴黎 找女人喝酒
A thou I leave here for seed when I get back.
留一千块在这儿,等回来用
And the rest I send to my mother.
剩下的寄给我妈
Oh,man,2500. And in Paris.
天啊!两千五百块,还有巴黎
You always was lucky.
你总是这么好运
Hey,remember that night in Fort Bragg?
还记得在布拉格堡那一晚吗?
I remember it.
记得
You know,I think I sneak over there and give it a big whang myself.
你知道,我应该试试手气的
Why not? What's to lose?
对啊,反正没什么可输的
Damn it.
糟糕
Why did he have to mention Fort Bragg?
他提布拉格堡干嘛?
I was lucky,all right, in that crap game.
我在一场赌局里赢了钱
Next day I break my leg in a jump.
第二天我跳伞断了腿
And two months in traction.
在医院躺了二个月
Twenty-five hundred dollars.
两千五百块
That's more money I ever had in my whole life.
我一辈子都没有拥有过这么多钱
I know.
但我知道不会有好事的
Man,I just know.
我可以感觉到
I wonder how long it takes to lose $2500.
不知道输掉两千五百块要多久
Pint of sludge,Ted.
来杯酒,泰德
Oh,hello,Dave. Hey,you seen Johnny?
嗨,大卫,看到强尼了吗?
Yes.
有
Well,where is he?
他在哪?
Come on,Dave.
告诉我
I need my boots. Johnny's borrowed them.
我要的靴子被他借走了
Where is he?
他在哪?
At the bottom...
躺在英伦海峡…
...of the Channel.
底下
You mean...
你是说…
...he's bought it?
他挂了吗?
Ack-ack over Calais.
他被防空炮打中
He jumped clean, but his parachute didn't open.
虽然跳了出来 可是伞打不开
That leaves just you in the squadron,Dave.
这个队只剩你一个了
I mean,of the old 1940 mob.
我是说同梯的只剩你了
What's always worried me about being one of the few...
我担心的是…
...is the way we keep on getting fewer.
队友一个个走了
Yeah.
对
Poor old Johnny.
可怜的强尼
Bad luck,it happening now.
运气真差,现在才发生
-Now,then. What's the difference? -He went through the Battle of Britain!
-那有什么差别? -我是说,他活过了英伦战役
And now if the big show starts tonight...
要是今晚开始进攻…
...he won't be in it.
他就无法参加了
Look,will you please shut up about him?
你可不可以不要再提他了?
All right,all right. I'm sorry,I'm sorry.
好,对不起,对不起
You heard something about tonight?
你听到什么关于今晚的事吗?
No,no. I haven't heard anything.
什么也没有
-What are you talking about then? -Well,it's just....
-那你在说什么? -只是…
-Go on,go on. -I have a feeling it's on for tonight.
-快说,快说 -我有个感觉就在今晚
-That's all. -A feeling.
-就这样 -一种感觉
Take your feeling somewhere else.
去你的烂感觉
I've got a letter to write.
我有信要写
I've had this feeling since I woke up.
我早上起来就有这种感觉
I've had it with me all day long.
整天都是这样
I can't shake it off.
一直有这种感觉
It's tonight. I know it is.
就是今晚,不会错
All right,it's tonight.
好,是今晚
Suits me fine.
我无所谓
Tonight. This afternoon. Now!
今晚,今天下午,现在
I mean...
最好是在…
...as soon as I finish this beer.
我一喝完啤酒后
-General,can you spare me a minute? -Come in.
-将军,有空吗? -进来
-Thank you. -Can I get you coffee?
-谢谢 -要咖啡吗?
-No,thanks. -I'll get some for myself.
-不了 -我自己来
Is it still raining?
还在下雨吗?
On and off,off and on.
时下时停
Sometimes I wonder which side God's on.
有时候我在想 上帝站在谁那边?
What?
什么?
I say,sometimes I wonder which side God's on.
我说,有时候我在想 上帝到底站在谁那边?
Good question.
这是个好问题
What's on your mind,Van?
你在想什么?
I'm concerned about the placement of our drop zones.
我担心伞兵们的降落点
Go on.
继续
I know this is a hell of a late date to bring up something new...
我知道现在要改太迟了…
...but you've given me a tough nut to crack.
可是你给了我个棘手的问题
-It gets tougher every time I try. -I know,Van.
-现在却更棘手了 -我知道,凡
the only road the Germans can use...
德军只能经过位在圣梅英格里斯的…
...to drive into our northern flank. But it has to be taken.
一条路到达我们的北侧 这个地点非被抢占住和…
And it has to be held.
坚守住不可
That's why I gave you the job,Van.
这就是为什么 需要你做的原因,凡
-Can I use your board? -Of course.
-可以借黑板一用吗? -当然
Here's the town. Heavily fortified.
还有这个镇布有重兵
Down here is the swamp area that the Germans have flooded.
这片沼泽区都是德军
And in between,four miles from the town,is our drop zone.
我们的伞兵 会在中间地带降落
Now,if anything goes wrong and we undershoot...
如果跳早了就会落在沼泽区…
...we land in this flooded area and are bogged down.
淹死在里面
If we overshoot,we come down like clay pigeons...
如果跳晚了…
...smack dab in the center
可能就会变成路上的活靶
That's why I gave the men training in low-level jumps near the villages.
我一直在村子附近训练士兵
So I've heard.
我知道
Got a complaint from the city council at Bexhall.
贝克荷斯镇有抱怨
Some of your men overshot the drop zone and landed in the town.
你的人跳离了指定点 着陆在村里,吓到了村民
-Tied up traffic for an hour. -That's true,sir. I was with them.
-也阻塞了交通 -没错,当时我和他们一起
Sudden crosswind hit us, swept us over the treetops...
突然遭遇强风…
...scattered us all over the place.
把大家都吹散了
-Where did you end up? -In the courtyard of a convent.
-你降落在哪? -在修道院里
Relax,Van. Sit down.
轻松点,凡,坐下
The last few months have been a tough grind on all of us.
大家在过去几个月都受够了
I hear you've been working yourself and your battalion hard.
你一直不停的鞭策…
Almost without a stop.
你和你的部队
Now that we're almost at the end of the line...
现在我们要准备行动了…
...why don't you try easing up on yourself and on the men?
干嘛不让你和大伙轻松一点?
Sometimes a battalion can be sharpened to too fine a point.
有时候军队和指挥官…
Sometimes a commander can too.
都可以被训练成为菁英
Well...
那么…
...if there's any further delay...
要是必须再延后…
...I request permission to submit a new placement for our drop zones.
我请求准许改换 跳伞降落地点
All right. Put it in writing.
用正式公文写下来
Make it official. That's your prerogative.
正式纪录下来,那是你的权利
But Ike has called a final meeting for tonight at Southwick House.
不过,艾森豪今晚 已经举行过最后会议了
If it's on,we'll get the green light by 9:30.
只要一声令下 今晚九点半就要行动了
-What are the chances? -Better than 50-50.
-机率怎么样? -机会很大
Forget everything I said. I got the best battalion in this division...
别再多想了 我有最好的军队…
...and they're ready.
而且都已就绪
Here it is. The latest report.
最新报告来了
-It's Southwick House,sir. -Stagg here.
-从总部打来的,长官 -我是史塔格
Yes,sir. The new front's moving in much faster than we thought.
新锋面动得比我们想得还要快
Yes,sir,it's definitely improving.
天气一定会变好
I'll be there,sir. 9:30.
我会到的,九点半
-Would you like some more tea,sir? -Coffee,and make it black.
-还要茶吗,先生? -咖啡,不加糖
Please.
麻烦
One moment,Colonel Priller.
等一下,普力勒上校
Why wasn't he court-martialed?
他为什么没受军法审判?
He shot down 132 planes.
他击落132架飞机
Hello,Pips,old boy.
(德军空军西区指挥总部)
Don't call me "Pips,old boy."
这个老家伙 别叫我“老家伙“
You were a rotten pilot when we flew in Russia.
我们在苏俄飞的时候 你就糟透了
You're flying a desk now,but you're still a rotten pilot!
虽然你现在作文职 还是个糟糕的飞行员
What's that you're saying?
哈哈,对不起,你刚说什么?
I'm squatting here on this God-forsaken airfield...
我现在待的这烂机场 只有两架飞机…
...with only two planes, two stinking crates!
两架老母鸡
Oh,sure,sure,your orders were followed!
没问题,你的命令一定照办
Now my squadrons are God-knows-where!
天晓得,我的队员在哪
My supplies are all gone. What am I supposed to do now?
弹药全没了,现在该怎么办?
But Pips,we had to disperse our fighter squadrons. We had to!
老家伙,我们非得分散战斗机队 非这样不可
Look what happened to our airstrips around the Pas-de-Calais!
看看我们在帕得加雷的跑道 变成什么样子了
The whole idea is absolutely idiotic!
这整个主意 真是白痴得可以
You move us back instead of forward!
你不但没带我们前进 还使我们后退
Sure,I know the weather's lousy and they probably won't invade...
好吧,但我知道天气很糟 对方不太可能进攻…
...but what would happen if they did?
万一进攻又会怎么样?
But you know I can't get there with my equipment for two days.
我的装备无法让我在两天内到达
I tell you,you're all crazy!
告诉你,你们全都疯了
Priller has always been a hothead...
普力勒一向这么火爆…
...but let's not underestimate him.
可是别低估他
What he says is not entirely illogical.
他的话还是满合逻辑的
What's the weather report?
天气报告怎么说?
Slightly better over the Channel.
海峡天气稍微转好
I wouldn't be surprised if--
我一点儿也不惊讶,如果…
-When's the next weather report? -Tonight at 8,general.
-何时有大消息? -今晚八点,将军
Keep me posted on the weather.
随时跟我报告最新的气候
You made my dinner reservations?
帮我订了晚餐约会吗?
Yes,I did,general.
订好了
Cancel everything.
取消它
-Have you got them? -Yes,sir.
-鞋子呢? -在这儿,长官
Let me have them.
给我
Shoes for my wife,I had them specially made in Paris...
鞋是要给我太太的 我特别在巴黎订作的
...for her birthday,tomorrow, the sixth of June.
明天六月六日是她的生日
Please wish her a happy birthday.
祝她生日快乐
Thank you,Speidel.
谢谢
Why didn't they attack in May? The weather was perfect....
他们为什么不五月进攻 当时天气那么好
Tides were right,and now....
潮汐是正确的…
An attack now would be embarrassing.
现在进攻会很糟
Let's go. But I don't think we need worry.
走吧,我不认为需要担心
Is the plan ready,sir?
计划好了吗?
Yes,yes,quite finished.
是的,差不多了
War games...
战争游戏…
...theoretical invasions.
是理论性的攻击
Rush to Rennes just to push little flags around a table.
快速推进到雷内 只为了插上军旗
Playing at war!
把战争当游戏
Do you win or lose,sir?
你是输还赢,先生?
Have I ever lost?
我输过吗?
But general,this time you play the role of Eisenhower.
可是将军,这次你扮演的 是艾森豪的角色
I win because I go against the rules.
我就是因为不按规矩才会赢
We expect them to cross at the narrowest part of the Channel...
我们本预期他们 会从海峡最狭窄的地方过来…
...and in good weather. But that's too simple,too obvious.
而且是趁好天气 可是这样未免太显而易见了
I choose the widest part,in the worst weather,and attack here.
我的话会选海峡最宽的地方 在最糟的天气下,然后攻打这里
In Normandy.
在诺曼第
And in bad weather!
天气最坏的时候
Like now...
就像现在…
...bad weather!
这种坏天气
Trying to pick a trend is difficult.
要找出趋势很难
From a meteorological standpoint, conditions almost resemble mid-winter.
从气象学上来看 现在的情况有如冬天
And Normandy?
诺曼第的天气如何?
High winds,clouds, and some fog over the beaches.
强风,海岸布满乌云
However,I can say with a certain degree of safety...
不过,我想多少可以确定地说…
...that we can expect a brief period of fair conditions.
天气会短暂转好
Let me summarize,then.
让我作个总结
What you're promising us is a barely tolerable period of fair conditions.
你能保证会有一阵子的好天气?
Am I right?
对吗?
Yes.
是的
Conditions that are far below the minimum requirements.
情况还是远低于可接受程度?
That's all I can promise.
我能保证的只有这样
You've done your best,Stagg. Thank you,gentlemen.
你尽力了,史塔格 谢谢
Well,there it is.
事情是这样的
We've postponed the attack once already.
我们曾延迟了攻击一次
Now,either we go on the sixth, with only marginal conditions...
要不我们就在六日时 趁稍稍转好的天气进攻…
...or postpone again...
或是再度延迟到…
...in the hope of getting perfect conditions.
天气完全变好
What do you think,Monty?
蒙提,你觉得呢?
I say,go. Go.
我赞成全力进攻
I must remind everybody...
我必须提醒各位…
...that the American convoy for the Omaha and Utah beaches...
前往奥玛哈和犹他海滩的…
...they've farthest to go...
美军派遣部队路程最长…
...must be given the order within the next half-hour...
在未来的半小时内…
...if the assault is to take place on the sixth.
他们必须得到遣派的命令
We can't keep almost a quarter of a million men on ships...
我们不能让25万名军人…
...in embarkation areas,indefinitely.
无止尽地在船上空等
The longer we wait,the more acute our security problem.
等的愈久 士兵的安全问题愈大
The next time...
下一个…
...the tides and the moon will be right....
涨潮的月夜…
Not before July.
要到七月以后
Gentlemen...
各位…
...such a postponement...
若要延后…
...is too bitter to contemplate.
会很痛苦
A brilliant plan,general. Unorthodox,but brilliant.
聪明的计划,将军 不按常理,但很聪明
Fortunately,it's only a game.
还好只是游戏而已
I don't think we have much to worry about.
我不认为需要去担心
Eisenhower would never take the gamble.
艾森豪不敢赌的
Never.
绝对不会
I'm quite positive we must give the order.
我确定必须下达命令
I don't like it...
我不想这样…
...but there it is.
但事实如此
Gentlemen...
各位…
...I don't see how we can possibly do anything else but go.
我看不出除了进攻之外 还有别的选择
Wilson speaking.
威尔逊报告
Yes,sir.
是的,长官
It's on,sir. Ike's made the decision. Tonight,as scheduled!
决定了,长官,就定在今晚
Colonel Tomson speaking.
这是汤姆森上校
Thank you.
谢谢
Next stop...
下一站…
...Normandy.
诺曼第
God help us now.
愿上天保佑
Lovat here.
我是洛维特特
Gentlemen...
各位…
...the day we've been waiting for has arrived.
等待的这天终于到了
Invasion! We're on our way.
我们要进攻了
General.
将军
The orders have been given. It's on.
命令下来了,准备进攻
Have the battalion commanders join me in the wardroom.
把部队指挥官找来
All right,sergeant.
可以了,下士
You men are the eyes of our airborne Army.
你的人 是我们空降部队的前锋
You,the pathfinders,will have one job,and one job only:
你们唯一的任务就是开路
To light the drop zones for our paratroops.
替我们的伞兵扫清降落地点
Along with the British and Canadians you'll be the first men...
你们和英国和加拿大的开路部队…
...to land in France. And remember this:
将是第一批登陆法国的人 记住…
When you get to Normandy...
到了诺曼第后…
...you'll only have one friend:
只有…
God.
求上帝保佑了
And this.
还有这把枪
This...
这是…
...is Rupert.
鲁伯
Now,we are going to drop Rupert...
我们要让鲁伯…
...and a lot more like him...
还有很多像他一样的人…
...behind the invasion area.
降落在攻击区后方
He's...
鲁伯…
...a very extraordinary fellow,Rupert.
是个了不起的人
He's a sort of...
他是那种…
...one-man army,all by himself.
擅于单兵行动者
Let me show you.
让我示范给你们看
Let me show you what happens when Rupert...
让我告诉你鲁伯落地后…
...hits the ground.
会发生什么事
Sergeant,switch off the lights,please.
下士,把灯关掉
All right,sergeant,that's all.
好,把灯打开
All right,come on. Simmer down.
各位,冷静下来
Come on,up.
快起来
It's possible that Rupert and his men will do the same thing to the Germans.
也许鲁伯和他的弟兄 会扰乱德军
Confuse them,make them look over their shoulders...
让他们分散注意力…
...and launch an attack in the wrong direction.
或许朝着错误方向攻击
Ten-hut!
注意!
-The crickets have been distributed. -So I heard.
-响板已经发下去了 -好,我知道了
At ease!
稍息
You're as ready as we can make you.
各位已经作好万全准备
This five-cent toy...
给各位的这响板…
...wasn't issued to you for laughs.
不是拿来开玩笑
It may save your life.
它可能会救你一命
You're gonna be landing in the dark.
各位将在黑暗中降落
On the other side of that hedgerow...
可能会…
...the fellow may not be wearing the same uniform you are. So...
遭遇敌军,所以…
...one click...
听到一响声后…
...is to be answered by two clicks.
用两响声回应
And if you don't get that answering click...
如果对方没回应…
...hit the dirt and open fire.
就开火
I repeat:
我再说一次…
One click...
听到一响声后…
...must be answered by two clicks.
用两响声回应
Now,hang on to this gimmick. It's as important as your weapon.
别弄丢这玩意 它和你的武器一样重要
-Do you read me? -Loud and clear,sir.
-懂吗? -听懂了,长官
All right. One more thing.
还有一件事
Your assignment tonight is strategic.
各位负有战略任务
You can't give the enemy a break.
别让敌人有喘息时间
Send them to hell.
送他们下地狱
That is all.
完毕
This is London calling. This is our eighth news bulletin.
在伦敦呼叫所有朋友
Here are some personal messages.
艾方索林纳斯 柯里威尔市市长
"Molasses tomorrow will bring forth cognac. "
“糖浆明天会制造出烈酒来”
"John has a long mustache. "
“约翰的八字胡很长”
I repeat:
我重复:
"John has a long mustache!"
“约翰的八字胡很长!”
No,not yet....
不,还没有…
Oh,my Lord!
天啊!
"John has a long mustache."
“约翰的八字胡很长”
Make any sense to you,mac?
你听的懂吗?
As I said last night,they're code messages to the Resistance chaps.
就像我昨晚说的 这些是给反抗军的代码讯息
Obviously,one message means something to one group...
很明显的,讯息对这个小组来说 是一种意思…
...and another means something to another group.
对另一个小组是另一种意思
"There is a fire at the travel agency. "
“旅行社着火了”
I repeat:
我重复一次:
"Wounds my heart with a monotonous languor. "
“让我的心有种单调的懒散”
The bridge,in 45 minutes.
45分钟内要到桥头
We'll be back.
我们会回来的
"Wounds my heart with a monotonous languor."
“让我的心有种单调的懒散”
I repeat:
我重复一次:
"There is a fire at the travel agency."
“旅行社着火了”
The best hand I've had all night.
今晚最好的牌
Let me see here....
让我看看…
Pardon me.
对不起
Pardon me,general,it's come.
对不起,将军,消息进来了
Wait. Give that to me.
等等,给我
What's come?
什么事?
It's the second part of the message.
这是讯息的第2部份
-Verlaine. -Yes. The second verse.
-是魏伦的诗 -是第二节
"Wounds my heart with a monotonous languor."
“用单调的沉闷伤害我的心”
We can expect the invasion within 24 hours!
24小时内可能会开始攻击
Put the 15th Army on full alert.
命令第15师全军戒备
Thank you.
谢谢
You know,I'm too old a bunny to get very excited about all this.
你知道 我老到对这一切都不在意了
Now,where was I? Oh,yes,two spades!
我该打什么?对了,黑桃二
It's almost impossible to believe.
简直无法相信
Every dot represents a ship.
每一点代表一艘船
You got battlewagons,cruisers, destroyers,minesweepers.
战舰,巡航舰 驱逐舰,扫雷舰
You got assault craft of every size and every type.
各种大小和类型的攻击船
The biggest armada the world's ever known.
这是史上最大的攻击行动
Here.
拿去
You remember it.
你会记得的
Remember every bit of it.
会记得这一切
We're on the eve of a day...
在我们死了很久之后…
...that people will talk about long after we're dead and gone.
大家都还会讨论到今天晚上的事
You wanna know something?
你知道吗?
It gives me goose pimples just to be part of it.
单是参与其中 就让我坐立不安了
You could call it one of them...
当然,这是…
...crazy,quickie wartime marriages, you know?
战前临别的快速结婚
Met at a dance at the USO and all that...
在舞会上认识的…
...but,I mean,I took it serious.
但我可是认真的
And so did she. We didn't do it just for kicks.
她也是,我们不是开玩笑的
-When did you get the letter? -Week ago.
-你何时收到信的? -二个星期前
Two weeks.
二个星期前
Maybe I was wrong,what I wrote her.
也许我不该写信给她
I mean,she's a high-class model and all,and I....
她可是个高贵的女人
I'm not the kind of guy to get married that easy.
我也不是随便就结婚的人
I mean,it wasn't no joke to me.
我不是在开玩笑
But oh,man,we really had some wonderful times together.
但我们真的一起有过 一段美好时光
And you think she's got a boyfriend?
你想她交了男朋友吗?
Well,she never actually said so....
她没说过,不过…
I mean....
我是说…
You think I was right? I mean,was I fair?
你觉得我对吗? 我公平吗?
She can't get one without your permission,right?
至少她没你的同意…
You gotta give your okay.
不能离婚
I know it's the law.
这就是法律
They passed it for all the Dear Johns.
为身为军人的丈夫所规定的
Well,I guess I better be getting back to the outfit.
我想我最好回部队去了
Good luck.
祝你好运
You too.
你也是
Who was that guy? The one you was talking to so long?
那个人是谁? 那个跟你说了很久的人是谁?
I don't know,Sparrow.
我不认识他
I never saw him before in my life.
从没见过那个人
Happy birthday,general, from your staff!
我们大家祝你生日快乐
Thank you.
谢谢
Will you cut the cake,sir?
要切蛋糕吗?
I trust you don't expect me to eat it too!
我相信你们 不会希望我一个人吃完
What's that?
那是什么?
Dummkopf,that's the "V for victory" sign. Three dots and a dash.
笨蛋,那代表胜利 三点一横
Ain't you never heard Beethoven's Fifth Symphony?
你没听过 贝多芬的第五交响曲吗?
Release point coming up, Major Howard.
霍华中校,快到降落地点了
Right,prepare for landing.
准备着陆
Cutting loose now.
准备降落!
Roger and out.
通话完毕
Major Howard...
(英军第六空降师先锋部队 约翰霍华中校)
...I cannot overestimate the importance of your task.
你的任务十分的重要
The Orne River Bridge must be captured...
奥纳河的桥一定在敌军炸毁之前…
...before the enemy can destroy it.
夺取成功
It's a vital military artery,and the enemy has prepared it for demolition.
这条桥是主要通道 敌军已准备好要炸桥
It must be taken by surprise and captured intact.
我们必须出其不意的将它攻占
Your gliders will land at night, without the benefit of ground support.
滑翔翼部队必须在 夜间无地面支援下着陆
You will assault the garrison, overwhelm it...
你们将要突击敌军…
...and hold until relieved.
而且坚持到最后
Major Howard!
霍华少校
There's the bridge coming up.
桥快到了
Just on our left.
在你的左手边
Right,link your arms.
各位手牵好
Brace yourselves.
抓稳了
Feet up!
准备好
Hang on!
撑着点
Smoke screen. Smoke.
烟雾弹
Up the action,bucks!
开始攻击…
Right,Tom. Over the bridge.
好,汤姆,到桥上去
Check for demolition charges!
清除爆裂物!
Hello! Hello!
喂!喂!
Hello! Damn it! Hello!
喂!糟糕!喂!
Clear.
准备好
It's working!
成功了!
Hello! Hello!
喂!喂!
-Where's the doc? -On the third glider.
-医生呢? -在第三滑翔翼
There's no report from them.
没有他的下落,长官
-Walsh. -Sir?
-瓦许? -长官
Tom,Ruskin and Royal have had it. Take over.
汤姆阵亡了,你去那边…
On the other end of the bridge.
接替他指挥
-What happened to you? -Broke it on landing.
-你怎么了? -我着陆时弄断了手臂
-Isn't the doc with you? -No,he's missing.
-医生和你在一起吗? -医生不见了
We crashed in the river. Afraid we've got a lot of casualties.
我们坠毁河中,伤亡惨重
I'm all right,sir. So are the boys.
我还好,长官 兄弟们也都还好
-Okay,carry on. -Right,sir. Come on!
-继续 -是的,长官,跟我来!
Well,I'll be....
嗯,我真的不…
Hey,doc! Doc!
嘿,医生
What are you doing there? That's the German side.
你在干什么? 那是德军的地方
Sir,anybody can make a mistake.
每个人都会犯错
Sir?
长官?
The demolition charges have been removed. It's all clear.
所有爆裂物都被拆除了
Good. Corporal Smith.
干得好,下士
Send out the success code words. Keep sending until acknowledged.
发送任务成功信号 一直到确认为止
-John,set up HQ in that pillbox. -Right,sir.
-在那座小碉堡成立总部 -是,长官
All in less than 15 minutes.
15分钟内弄好
Only a matter of time before they counterattack.
对方马上会反攻的
-What about the paratroopers? -7th Para might not get here for hours.
-伞兵呢? -伞兵可能要几小时后才到
And Lovat and his commandos....
洛维特和他的部队…
It could be midday before they get here.
到的时候可能已经中午了
The question is, how long can we hold?
问题是我们能坚守多久?
Hold until relieved.
坚守到最后
What awful weather. It's raining again.
天气真糟糕 又下雨了
Thank you.
谢谢
Did you get the list?
收到时间表了吗?
General Schlieben of the 709th has already left for the war games.
有,709师的施里本将军 已经赶来加入战局了
The commander of the 243rd left for Rennes at 1800 hours.
243师会在晚上六点前往雷纳
Who else?
还有谁?
Also,Zimmermann of the 352nd, 12 officers in all.
还有352师的齐默曼 总共12名军官
Yes,I know.
是的,我知道
The weather is bad,so everyone enjoys an extra night in Rennes.
因为天气很糟,所以每个人 会在雷纳多待一晚
I don't like it.
我不喜欢这样
Any of it.
一点都不喜欢
So many key officers are away at the same time.
太多重要军官 在同一时间离开
I don't know why,but I don't like it.
我不懂为什么 我就是不太喜欢这样
But the war games have been scheduled for a week....
可是这在一星期前 就安排好了
Yes,for tomorrow,not tonight.
是,但那是明天的事
Advise all officers who have not yet left for Rennes...
告诉所有还没离开 雷纳的军官…
...to postpone their departure until tomorrow.
把行程延到明天
May I remind you,general...
容我提醒您,将军…
...that the Allies have always landed in perfect weather conditions.
盟军一向是趁天气好才着陆的
North Africa,Sicily,Italy....
在北非,西西里 意大利都是如此…
Yes,and always at dawn.
而且都是在黎明的时候
We're 11 minutes from the green light.
还有11分钟就要出发了
Now,once more,I repeat:
我再重覆一次:
If,for any reason,we fail to hit our drop zones...
不论什么原因 导致未能在指定地点降落…
...move north by east.
就朝东北方前进
North by east.
记得是东北方
The Germans have flooded large swamp areas behind the coast.
德军已占领了 海岸后方的大部份沼泽地
Avoid them if possible.
尽可能避开他们
We came here to fight,not to swim.
我们是去作战 不是去游泳的
Do you read me?
了解吗?
Loud and clear,sir.
非常清楚,长官
How'd you make out?
结果如何?
How did you make out at the game?
手气如何?
I lost.
我输了
Now we're both jumping clean.
我们现在已经摆脱恶运了
I understand. And when will the field marshal return?
我懂 司令官什么时候会回来?
I see. Oh,well.
喔,等一下
Just a moment.
等等
The radar report.
雷达报告给我
We are getting reports of strong radar interference...
我们收到有强烈的雷达干扰…
...and radio reception is jammed.
无线电讯也受阻
I realize this has happened before, but never this effectively!
我知道这以前发生过 可是从没像这样过
And the--
那个…
Call the OB West? Very well.
通知西线统帅部?很好
Give my respects to the field marshal when he returns.
司令官回来时 替我问候他
Bye,Rupert. Do your duty for God,king,and your country.
再见,鲁伯,替上帝、领袖 还有你的国家好好的表现吧
Call for reinforcements! We're under attack!
请求增援,我们受到攻击!
Forward! Board! Fast!
往前!快!
-Are we late? -No,but...
-迟到了吗? -没有,但是…
...we must hurry!
我们得快点
What is it?
这是什么?
I'll go.
我去
Stop!
停住!
We said,stop!
我叫你停下来!
Stop,or I'll shoot!
不停我就开枪了
What are you doing here?
你在这儿干嘛?
I live in that farm.
我住在那个农场上
Nobody lives in that farm.
那里没人住
-It's abandoned. -Show me your papers.
-那是废弃的农场 -给我看证件
Hurry up!
快点!
Come with me.
跟我来
Go on!
去啊!
Put your bicycle there.
把车停在那
Hans!
汉斯!
Hans,where are you?
汉斯,你在哪?
-What's going on here? -Nothing!
-怎么了? -没事情!
Who is with you? I want to know!
谁跟你一起来?告诉我
Stop!
停下来!
Good luck at the war games,general.
将军,希望你游戏战事玩的开心
Anything important?
有重要消息吗?
Communications reports difficulty in contacting our forward posts.
通讯兵报告 已和前哨部队取得联络
The Underground again!
又是反抗军的问题
Some sort of rubber dummies have been dropped by parachute.
对方用降落伞 空降了一些橡胶假人
Rubber dummies!
橡胶假人?
Connect me with General Richter!
通信兵,帮我接雷克将军
We can expect commando raids and other diversionary tactics...
原以为可能会遭遇 一些攻击和其它战术行动
...but I don't like this idea of dummy parachutists.
但我不喜欢空降的假人
Marcks speaking. Yes.
我是马可,是的
Are you certain?
你确定?
How many?
有多少?
What do you think of it?
你的看法呢?
Thank you,Richter.
谢谢你
Paratroopers reported here, here and here!
空降部队要到这边 这边还有这边…
Put it over there.
放在那边
This is what they dropped,they explode on contact with the earth.
他们丢假人下来 一碰到地面就爆炸
In the dark,they look like soldiers.
在黑暗中看起来好像真人
Perhaps these are what General Richter saw,not real paratroopers.
也许就像雷克将军看到的一样 那些不是真人
When you create a diversion, it's for a reason.
每种攻击都有原因的
Connect me with General Pemsel!
给我接潘赛尔将军
Dummies...!
假人?
Rubber dummies!
橡胶假人!
I agree with you,general. I'll call you back.
我同意你说的 将军,我再回你电话
What about my call to von Rundstedt?
接通范鲁斯塔特了吗?
We haven't been able to reach him. The main lines seem to be cut.
没办法联络上 主要线路好像被切断了
Colonel Helmdach is trying to re-route the call.
海姆达区上校准备另外接驳线路
They wouldn't drop dummies...
他们不会空降假人…
...unless it was to divert our attention from something else.
除非他们是要 转移我们的注意力
In this weather?
在这种天气?
In any kind of weather!
任何天气都有可能
I must get in touch with OB West.
我一定要联络西线统帅部
They're enemy paratroopers!
他们是敌军的空降部队!
Blimey,mate...
好心一点…
...you'll wake up the whole blooming German Army!
你会吵醒整个德军的
Fellas!
同志们!
I'm hung up!
我被卡住了
-Are you all right? -Yeah.
-还好吗? -还好
Where have you come from?
你从哪里来的?
Awfully sorry,old man.
真是抱歉,老头
Simply landed here by accident.
只是刚好降落在这里
What's that?
怎么了?
Sorry I startled you. I'm trying to find my communion set.
抱歉吓到你了 我只是要找我的圣餐餐具
-Your what? -My communion set. I've lost it.
-你的什么? -圣餐餐具,我把它弄丢了
Now listen,padre. We've got no time to look for--
听好,没时间了,神父…
I'm sure that it was here that I lost it.
我确定掉在这儿
We're under fire,padre. Don't you think we ought to--?
我们受到攻击,神父 你不觉得我们应该…
You go on,my boy. Go on. I'm sure I shall only be a minute.
你先去吧,我马上就好
Cor! Stuff a grouse.
我的老天爷啊
I've got it! I've got it!
找到了!…
Glory be.
太好了
Now,my son,let's go about God's work this night.
我们去完成上帝的使命吧
Pluskat.
我是普鲁斯卡
Hello,Pluskat! Do you hear me?
嗨,普鲁斯卡,听得到吗?
Nothing that I've heard....
我都没听到什么…
The usual bombing,but quite distant.
有爆炸声,但是很远的样子
Oh,yes,I can hear it.
我听得到
Well,wait a minute.
等等
Yes,just a moment.
等一下
Flares,but a long way up the coast.
有火光,但在海岸附近
Yes,Cherbourg is getting hit again.
是的,雪堡又被攻击了
There's probably nothing to it...
可能没什么事吧
...but we have had reports of paratrooper landings.
不过我们收到 有伞兵降落的报告
I'll go to my bunker and take a look.
我去弹药库看一看
Thank you,sir.
谢谢,长官
Higher! Higher!
再高一点…
Louis,open your store. We need more buckets!
路易斯,把门打开 我们需要桶子
Mayor Renaud,you must come with me immediately.
雷诺市长 你一定得立刻跟我来
-Is it important? -Very important,Mayor Renaud.
-有什要紧事吗? -很重要
What's wrong,madam?
怎么了,女士?
I was on my way to the little house outside....
刚刚我正要去小屋的时候…
Yes,yes,go on.
是的,是的,继续
Suddenly,I saw a man fall from the sky.
突然看到有人从天而降
-A parachutist? -Yes,that's right.
-伞兵? -是的,没错
He looked like a big white bird!
好像一只白色大鸟
-British or German? -What?
-是英军还是德军? -什么?
The parachutist,was he a friend or an enemy?
伞兵,是我方还是敌方?
I don't know. He disappeared without a word. Just "Shh!"
我不知道 他只说“嘘”,然后就不见了
-Without a word? -Just "Shh!"
-什么都没说? -他只说“嘘”
Bonjour,madame...
早,女士
...je suis americain.
我们是美国人
Bonjour,mademoiselle...
早,小姐
We seem to be circling.
我们好像在绕圈子
Maybe they're having difficulty finding the drop zone.
也许他们找不到空降点
Je suis...
我们是…
...americain.
美国人
Je suis americain.
我们是美国人
Voulez-vous...
怎么了…
...mademoiselle?
小姐?
Okay.
好了
Go!
跳!
Go! Go! Go!
跳!…
Paratroopers!
空降部队!
Paratroop groups. Those are paratroop groups!
是空降部队…
Anything new?
有新消息吗?
Heavy bombing over Cherbourg as usual,sir...
还是一样,雪堡受到猛烈轰炸
...and now near Caen.
现在接近到凯恩了
The lines to Stations 6 and 8 have been cut...
接到第六和第八区的线路断了
...but the direct line is open.
可是专线还可以通
I'll stay for a while.
我再等一下
-Would you like coffee? -Yes,thank you.
-要咖啡吗? -好,谢谢
For God's sakes,padre, stop that damn noise.
神父,别再发出噪音
I'm sorry,son. I'm afraid I'm lost.
对不起,我想我迷失了
Well,who ain't? Now,come on.
谁不是呢?来吧
Two clicks.
两声响
I heard two clicks.
我听到两声响了
Man...
哇…
...am I glad to see you.
真高兴见到你们
-You guys the 82nd? -No. This is the 101.
-你们是第82空降师的吗? -不是,是第101师
101?
101师?
Where's the 82nd?
那82师去哪了?
Look,bud,we don't even know where our own outfit is.
我们连自己的部队 都不知道在哪
Well,somebody's shooting at somebody.
某人在攻击某人
Let's us go find this war.
去看看
Come on.
来吧
Maybe they're Limeys and ain't got no cricket.
也许是英军 他们没有响板
They must be our guys.
那一定是我们的人
Okay.
好
No.
糟糕
Hey.
嗨
Hey,they were Germans.
是德军耶
Hundreds of planes have been flying to my left and right.
好几百架飞机到处在飞
Toward Caen.
往凯恩出发
Yes.
对
Now over the Cherbourg peninsula. Something must be happening!
现在飞过雪堡半岛了 一定出事了
But what,Pluskat,what? I haven't the faintest idea.
可是是什么呢,普鲁斯卡? 我一点头绪都没有
Has anything been observed on the beaches?
海岸上有动静吗?
No,nothing.
没…有
Yes,I'll let you know right away.
是的,我会立刻通知你
Of course.
当然
Are you positive that ankle's broken?
你确定脚踝断了吗?
Compound fracture,sir.
是多处骨折
Well,put the boot back on and lace it up,tight.
把靴子穿回去,然后绑紧鞋带
Don't get mad,I didn't break it.
别对我发脾气 不是我弄骨折的
And you're not walking on it.
但是你不用靠它走路
-You're not going to try-- -Knock it off and do as you're told.
-上校,你不是想要我… -别说了医生,照命令做
Yes?
是的?
A,B and C Company are scattered all over like we are.
A,B,C这三连 散的像我们一样到处都是
Go on.
继续说
Conklin landed on a stone wall,broke his shoulder. I left him with a medic.
康克林上校落在石墙,肩膀骨折 我把他留给救护队照顾
Any contact with F Company?
F连呢?
No,but they must be up ahead
一定在我们前方 靠近圣梅英格里斯的地方
Well,go ahead. Tie it off. Tie it off.
嗯,快点,快绑啊 快绑啊
Well,here's where we are.
这是我们所在的位置
The northern edge of the swamp area...
是沼泽地的北边…
...five miles from our drop zone.
离降落预定地5里
Five miles.
5里
-F Company? -No,sir.
-F连呢? -找不到F连
And we've got scouts all over the place.
到处都有侦查兵
We even picked up a group from the 101.
我们碰到了第101师的人
F Company were the first of the lead planes.
F连是在带头的飞机上
Well,give me a hand.
帮我一下
Can I have my rifle?
可以把枪拿给我吗?
Well,we'll head out this way.
我们朝这个方向走
We ought to reach high ground and open country by daybreak.
应该会在清晨时 碰到高地和空旷地
All right. Have the men spread out...
叫大家分散开来
...pick up any stragglers they can find.
还有让走失的士兵 暂时归队
-Pass the word. -Right,sir.
-把话传下去 -是
All right,men,spread out. Pick up stragglers you see.
叫大家分散开来 还有让走失的士兵暂时归队
Pass the word down.
把话传下去
All right...
好…
...let's go.
出发了
From the latest reports, this is how I see it:
从报告来看 我的看法是…
American paratroopers have landed....
美国空降部队已经降落了…
...here.
就在这里
British paratroopers here.
英国伞兵在这儿
The invasion....
这是侵略…
...here.
这里
Yes. Thank you,Pemsel.
是的,谢谢,潘赛尔
General Pemsel is convinced that this is the invasion.
潘赛尔将军相信 这是项侵略行动
I do not agree with him. This is my conclusion:
我不同意,我的结论是…
Normandy is the objective of a diversionary attack.
诺曼第是击东声西的目标
A diversionary attack,Blumentritt.
击东声西而已
It's not the main attack. That will come at the Pas-de-Calais...
这不是主要攻击点 主要攻击会是在帕得加雷…
...where it was always expected.
正如我们一向预期的
Where we always expected it.
如我们所一直预期
But we can't take any chances.
但我们不能冒险
I want the reserve panzers moved up at once!
叫装甲兵立刻出动
We need approval from the F¨¹hrer's headquarters.
要得到总部的同意才行
They wouldn't dare refuse me!
他们不敢拒绝我的
Call the F¨¹hrer's headquarters and insist.
打电话给总部说非得这么做
Insist that the panzers be released to me immediately!
叫他们一定要把装甲队交给我
An invasion of Normandy would be against all military logic.
攻击诺曼第不合军事逻辑
It would really be against all logic.
完全不合任何逻辑
Well,that about covers it,gentlemen.
大概就是这样了,各位
Most of you have had your feet wet before:
过去各位都有海岸登陆的经验
Dunkirk,Dieppe,Norway.
像在登克尔克,迪佩还有挪威
And we know what it means to be driven into the sea.
我们知道又被逼回海上是什么意思
In a few hours we're going back from the sea.
现在我们要再从海上进攻
And this time we're going to stay.
这一次非成功不可
There's no time for any sob stuff about...
没时间再担心…
...England,home and beauty.
英国,家乡和美女了
Remember,our people have had a rough time for four and a half years.
我们要担心的是 我们受了四年半苦的弟兄
They've earned the final victory.
他们赢得了最后胜利
Let's give it to them.
让我们去嘉奖他们
And to our French comrades in arms, I say:
我要告诉法国同胞们…
Good luck.
祝你好运
Tomorrow morning,we'll take them.
我们明天会收拾他们的
Come in,Teddy. That will be all,sergeant.
请进,泰迪
Did you have to put it in writing?
你一定要提出正式报告吗?
I knew you wouldn't let me go unless I did.
否则你不会让我去
You're putting me on the spot.
你真是让我难做
-I didn't mean to,Tubby. -The hell you didn't.
-我不是故意的,托比 -才怪
You put that request in writing, made it official.
你故意要提出正式报告
You're the assistant division commander.
你是副指挥官啊
And that's why I'm supposed to go ashore in the first wave.
所以我要到第一线去
That's where I'm supposed to be. You know that.
那是我该去的地方
You're important to this operation.
你对这个计划很重要
We can't have you knocked off on the first day.
我们不能让你第一天就阵亡
But that's not the real reason.
但是那不是真的理由
Isn't it because my father was president of the United States?
是因为我父亲是 美国总统的关系吗?
And a great president.
他是个好总统
And a great soldier.
也是个好军人
He led the charge of the Rough Riders up San Juan Hill.
他赢了圣璜山战役
So now you've got to be the first man ashore on Utah Beach.
所以你必须是 第一个登陆犹他海岸的人
But that's where I'm supposed to be, Tubby. That's my job.
那里是我该去的 那是我的职责
Also,I've been there side by side with the men all through training.
我和这些弟兄一起同甘共苦
They're used to seeing me there. They have a right to expect me there.
他们习惯有我了 他们有权期待我到场
President's son or not.
不管我父亲是不是总统
Is my request denied?
我的要求被拒绝了吗?
No,you know it's not.
你知道不会的
Request reluctantly approved.
非常不情愿地核准了
Thanks,Tubby.
谢谢,泰比
Thanks a lot.
很感激
Say...
嗯…
...how's that arthritis of yours?
你的关节炎怎么样?
Arthritis?
关节炎?
Haven't had a touch in months.
几个月没发作了
Glad to hear it.
那很好
The street...
街道…
...the bridge...
桥梁…
...the hotel...
旅馆…
...the casino.
赌场
That's it,gentlemen.
就这样子了,各位
One more thing....
还有…
You have been fighting everywhere for four years...
过去四年你们一直转战各地…
...in Abyssinia,Libya,Egypt,Crete....
在阿比西尼亚,利比亚 埃及,克里特…
But this time you are going to fight on French soil...
但是这一次 你们要在法国领土上作战…
...in our fields...
在我们的土地上…
...in our villages...
在我们的家园中…
...under the eyes of our own people.
在同胞的面前
I can't wake the F¨¹hrer on the strength of contradictory reports.
(第3师师长) (亚佛瑞朱铎将军)
He was up till four. He took a sedative and then retired.
我不能拿这些互相矛盾的报告 去吵醒元帅
I won't wake him for these reports.
元帅服了镇定剂 我不能拿这些报告去吵醒他
First we hear that the paratroopers are shot down plane crews.
起初我们听到的是 伞兵是被击落飞机上的士兵
Next they are identified as mechanical dummies.
然后又说是假人
If these reports are true and paratroopers have landed...
要是伞兵着陆了…
...it can only be a commando raid.
可能只是突击而已
Is that a sufficient reason to send the panzers to the coast?
这样足以构成 派遣装甲兵的理由吗?
I will submit all reports to the F¨¹hrer as soon as he awakens.
元帅醒来后 我会尽快把报告交给他
I understand.
我知道
JodI has turned us down.
朱铎将军回绝了
He will not release the panzers without the F¨¹hrer's approval...
没有元帅的核准 他不会把装甲队给我们
...and the Fuhrer is still asleep!
而元帅还在睡觉
Will you tell von Rundstedt?
可以告诉范鲁斯塔特吗?
No,not now....
不,不要现在
Not now.
不要现在
Thank you,gentlemen.
谢谢,各位
Sit down.
请坐
This is history.
这是历史性的一刻
We are living a historical moment.
我们活在历史性的一刻
We are going to lose the war...
我们要输掉战争了
...because the glorious F¨¹hrer has taken a sleeping pill...
因为我们的元帅 吃了安眠药
...and is not to be awakened.
而且不想被吵醒
It's unbelievable.
真不能令人相信
Think of it,Kurt.
想看看,克特
Don't ever forget it.
千万别忘记了
We are witnessing something...
我们正在见证一件事…
...which historians will always say is completely improbable...
史学家会说这是不可能的…
...and yet it is true.
但是这是千真万确的
The Fuhrer is not to be awakened!
竟然不愿意叫醒元帅
I sometimes wonder whose side God is on.
有时我怀疑上帝站在谁那边
Can I...
我能不能…
...bring you anything,sir?
帮你准备点什么喝的?
In my room there is a bottle of excellent cognac...
我房间里有一瓶上等白兰地…
...Napoleon,unopened.
还没开过的拿破仑
I was even saving it for a fitting occasion.
我是要留在适当时机喝的
This isn't exactly the right occasion,but get it anyway.
现在也许不适当 不过还是拿来喝了吧
Daylight at last.
终于天亮了
A whole night wasted again!
浪费了一个晚上
Where's my dog?
我的狗呢?
He was here a minute ago.
不知道,刚才还在这儿
Let's have one last look.
再看最后一眼吧
Nothing.
什么都没有
Not even a seagull....
连只海鸥都没有…
My God!
我的天
The invasion.
这是侵略行动
They're coming!
他们来了
Everyone to your posts!
回到岗位上!
It's the invasion! There must be 5000 ships out there!
这是侵略行动 海上一定有五千艘船
Get hold of yourself,Pluskat.
控制一下自己,普鲁斯卡
The enemy doesn't have even half that many.
敌人的船 连那个数字的一半都不到
Well,damn it! Come and see for yourself,you fool!
该死,你自己来看,你这笨蛋
It's amazing.
真令人惊讶
It's beyond belief.
真想不到
My dear Pluskat,where are these ships heading?
亲爱的普鲁斯卡 那些船要开向哪里?
SStraight for me!
开向我们!
General,in exactly two minutes...
将军,舰队再2分钟…
...the fleet will open fire.
就要开火了
Your attention,please. The admiral has an announcement.
注意,将军要讲话了
Soon we will have the honor to be engaged in battle.
我们马上就可以荣誉地参战了
To drive the enemy out,we must fire on our homeland.
为了驱走敌军,不得不在 我们自己的土地上开火
This is the price of liberty.
这就是自由的代价
Long live France!
法国万岁!
There he goes,right on time,as usual.
来的正是时候,和往常一样
They're landing! They're coming! They're coming!
他们到了,他们到了
I'm not crazy. Look,they're landing!
我没有发疯,看,他们到了
The Americans,the English and the French!
有美军,英军,法军
Do you hear me? What's the matter with you? What's going on?
你听得到我吗?你怎么了? 发生了什么事?
You must be deaf! Can't you...
你一定是聋了,你就不能…
Damn it,can't you hear it for yourself?
该死,你听不见吗?
We're under fire. Yes,under fire!
我们正在被攻击!
Those 5000 ships you say the Allies haven't got...
你说盟军没有五千艘船…
...well,they've got them!
你错了!
It's wonderful!
太好了!
Yes? What is it now?
遵命,又有什么事?
Listen to me,Pips.
听我说…
The invasion has started! Put yourself on alert at once!
攻击已经开始了 立刻将你自己武装起来
What the hell can I do with only two planes?
我只有两架飞机,能干什么?
Where are the others,you idiots?!
其他人呢?你们这些笨蛋
Priller,that's an order! Get ready at once! Understand?
普利尔,那是命令 立刻准备好,懂吗?
If it isn't too much trouble...
如果不麻烦的话…
...would you tell me where the invasion is?
可以告诉是哪儿被攻击?
What? Normandy! How delightful!
诺曼第,真是好啊
Thanks,my faithful Hans. That's the end for us! So long!
谢了,可靠的朋友 这次我们完了,永别了
It's getting very difficult to get any sleep around here.
在这里永远都会被吵到睡不着
Your prospects for a long sleep are excellent. The invasion has begun.
准备长眠吧,攻击已经开始了
Normandy. We're flying there,the two of us.
诺曼地,我们正向那儿飞去 我们两个人
Nobody else is left.
只有我们了
I don't think we're coming back.
我想我们不会再回来了
Move out! Move out!
全速前进…
The shelling has stopped.
轰炸停止了
Landing craft approaching.
登陆船接近了
Return to headquarters. Direct your troops from there!
回到总部来指挥你的部队
Those French bastards!
那些法国混球!
Sergeant!
中士!
Send this to headquarters by courier.
快递到总部去
No! Take it yourself. Tell them our lines are cut!
不,你自己拿去 告诉他们线路被切断了
Gentlemen,come here please.
各位请过来
Attack!
冲啊
Fast!
快点!
Take your positions!
到岗位上去!
Don't let them get too close!
不要让他们太靠近
Fast!
快点!
Attack!
快攻击!
There it is,men. Omaha Beach,dead ahead.
到了,各位 奥玛哈海滩在正前方
Lock on the target!
锁定目标!
Stand by!
准备好!
Get off of the beach!
快离开海滩
Let's go!
出发!
Come on,move up!
快点,动作快!
Hello,general,sir.
你好,将军
-Are you all right,boy? -Yes,sir.
-你还好吗,老弟? -很好,长官
Don't you think you better go back and get your rifle?
你不认为带着枪好一点吗?
Out there,sir?
你是说出去吗?
You're almost sure to need it before this day is over.
今天结束前你一定会需要的
Yes,sir.
是,长官
Come on! Move on up! Let's go.
快,快,动作快
Medic! Medic!
救护!救护!
General,first reports from Omaha,sir.
将军,奥玛哈来了第一份报告
"Assault teams have landed.
突击部队已登陆
No direct radio contact, but destroyers report...
无线电尚未接通 驱逐舰的报告显示…
...first and second waves appear pinned down on the beach.
不过第一和第二波 似乎已顺利登陆
Concentrated artillery and mortar fire.
受到猛烈地 重型武器和迫击炮的攻击
Third wave floundering." Heavy casualties,sir.
第三波失败,伤亡惨重,长官
When the mortars and machine guns are silenced...
等敌军炮火暂停后…
...have the battalion commanders join me over there.
我要见部队指挥官 在那边
Okay.
好的
Hang on to that map case,Eddie.
地图箱不要弄丢了,艾迪
I made it.
我做到了
Hey,I made it.
嘿,我做到了
Did you see me get those two guys?
你看到我击倒了两个人吗?
Hey,sergeant?
中士
As best as I can figure it, this is the wrong beach.
照我猜测,这不是预定的海滩
We're a mile and a quarter south of where we were supposed to land.
我们离预定登陆点还向北了一里
We should be up there.
我们应该在那边的
Control boat must've been confused by the naval bombardment smoke.
指挥船一定被炮火烟雾弄混了
I agree with you, but what will we do now?
我同意,那该怎么办?
Reinforcements and heavy equipment will approach in a very few minutes.
援兵和重武器很快就要到了
-I know,I know. -What if they land at the right beach?
-我知道,我知道 -如果他们在正确地点登陆的话呢?
The reinforcements will have to follow us wherever we are.
不论我们在哪 援兵都会跟着我们的
We're starting the war from right here.
我们就从这儿开战
-Head inland. We're going inland. -Okay,let's go.
-向内陆进攻 -好,出发
Follow me. Do everything I do!
跟着我,照着我做
All right. Let's go!
好,出发
Head for home!
向家乡前进
The Luftwaffe has had its great moment!
这真是最伟大的一刻
Stand by to beach.
到海滩待命
Duncan,take care of that strongpoint.
拿下敌军坚强守护的据点
Any minute now. Stand by!
马上准备行动,待命
Let's give it them back for Dunkirk!
报敦克尔克之仇
You hear that? Dunkirk. Do you hear it,Clough?
你听到了吗?敦克尔克
Sure he was at school at the time.
他那时候还在读书呢
Come on,you bums!
冲啊,你们这些无赖!
Come out,you dirty slobs! Flanagan's back!
快点,你这脏猪 佛拉拿根回来了
The evil of it all. Drowning a man before he fights.
太狠了,竟不给我机会去作战
Oh,come on!
快!
Keep those vehicles moving!
车子不要停下来
MP,chase out those cyclists.
宪兵,去追那些人
Get off the beach!
离开海岸,朝内陆前进
Move inland!
(考林莫指挥官 英国皇家海军海滩指挥官)
Come on,you lot!
你们快点!
Hurry it up.
快啊
Never mind the blathering!
别说闲话了
We must put these down somewhere.
我们一定要找个地方放好装备
The sooner you get off the beach...
等你们离开海滩后…
...the sooner they'll stop this blasted shelling.
他们就会停止轰炸
It's very bad for the dog!
对狗狗没好处的
Down,Winston,down!
过来,温斯顿,过来
Beach Master Sword,Section 2-A.
这是剑滩第二区指挥官
Third wave ashore on time. No obstruction to follow-up.
第三波顺利上岸 现在等候进一步指示
Standing by.
待命中
Get going!
快点行动!
For heaven's sake, get that carrier off the beach!
把车开离海滩
I was told I could transmit a newsflash on your radio.
有人告诉我 可以用你的无线电传送消息
If you can't drive it,carry it!
要是开不走就用抬的
You were saying?
你刚说什么?
I was told I could transmit a newsflash on your--
我听说我可以 借你的无线电…?
My dear fellow,I don't want to appear uncooperative--
老哥,并非我不合作…
Yes,I know all about the power of the press.
我知道媒体的力量
But this line happens to be rather busy! Come on!
可是这条线相当忙
Down,Winston. Down,Winston.
冷静,温士顿,冷静
What did he say?
他说什么?
The answer is no.
他说不行
We have to use the damn pigeons.
我们得用信鸽了
I've got these ready.
我早准备好了
Here,clip this on.
绑上去吧
They're going the wrong way.
方向错了
Not toward the Germans,you idiots!
那边是德军,你这白痴
The other way! The other way!
另一边!…
Damned traitors!
该死的叛徒
-Hold it. -Can't you get your finger out?
-拿住 -你的手指头卡住了吗?
-What's the matter? -Engine won't start,sir.
-怎么了? -引擎发不动,长官
Full of seawater,I think.
里面都是水
My old grandmother used to say...
我祖母常说…
...anything mechanical, give it a good bash.
如果不是机械问题就用踢的
Try it now.
现在试
Thank you,sir.
谢谢,长官
Off you go. Good luck.
干得好,祝好运
I'm sure that got it out.
我确定那车子怕被打
That's what I call a hell of a man!
他真是了不起
Aye,I like his dog too.
我也喜欢他的狗
Don't stand there yapping!
别再饶舌了
This isn't Hyde Park Corner! The war's over there!
我们可不是来玩的 战争就在眼前
Come along!
快
-Thank you. -Everything's going according to plan.
-谢谢 -一切都照计划进行
Stand by to move. Millin,"Blue Bonnet."
待命行动 米伦,吹《蓝边帽》
What in God's name...
这到底是什么…?
Oh,my friends. What a day! What a day!
噢,我的朋友,多美的一天
Welcome to France. Welcome to Colleville!
欢迎来到法国!
Most kind of you. Very nice to meet you--
你真好,高兴认识你
Look at this. I kept it for you all.
不过我替各位准备了这个
But I don't think there will be enough for everyone.
但我想可能不够
Perhaps next time. We have a previous engagement:the war!
也许下次吧 还有仗等着我们打
Mustn't lose that champagne!
我们可不想打输
All right,men,fall in! Millin,"Blue Bonnet."
全力进攻,兄弟们 米伦,吹《蓝边帽》
Goodbye.
再见
Thank you,boys! Thank you!
谢谢你们!谢谢!
Long live France! Long live the Allies!
法国万岁! 盟军万岁!
If you ask me,Flanagan...
我跟你说,佛兰根…
...there's a lot of very peculiar blokes on this beach.
这海滩上什么怪人都有
Welcome!
欢迎各位!
Welcome to you all!
欢迎各位
Thank you,dear,they're lovely!
谢了,亲爱的,真是可爱的鞋子
Better try them on first.
最好先穿看看
Rommel speaking.
我是隆美尔
Good morning.
早
What?
什么?
Where?
哪里?
Normandy!
诺曼第
Have they a foothold already?
盟军登陆了吗?
They must be thrown back!
他们一定要被击退了
What about the panzer reserves?
那后备装甲队呢?
Did von Rundstedt obtain their release from the F¨¹hrer?
鲁斯塔特从元帅那儿 获得指挥权了吗?
Normandy,Normandy.
诺曼第…
How stupid of me!
我真是笨
Stupid.
笨死了
There it is.
到了
You mean to tell me that's all we gotta climb?
我们要爬的山就那么高吗?
They're not as high as the practice ones.
练习爬的山比较高
They wasn't shooting at us then.
那么他们不是在对我们开火
Why can't the Air Force or Navy do this job?
空军和海军该作好他们的工作
The big guns in bunkers behind the cliff can't be seen from the air.
从空中看不到大炮
We knock them out or they'll murder our guys on the beach.
我们要去摧毁它们,不然他们会杀了 我们在海滩上的弟兄们
Yeah,well,if you ask me...
对,嗯,如果你问我…
...three grandmothers with brooms could sweep us off there...
随便来个部队 就可以把我们都杀光
...like flies off of a sugar cake.
而且片甲不留
That's it,the one we're after.
那就是我们的目标
It's empty.
是空的
The Air Force and Navy really plastered this baby.
空军和海军真的毫不留情
But I don't get--
但我不懂…
The guns.
这些枪…
There ain't no mounts.
没架好
They've never even been installed.
根本就没装好
You mean...
你是说…
...we come up all this way...
我们废了 这么大力气来到这儿…
...for nothing?
却毫无意义?
Don't worry,sarge, you'll be all right.
别担心,没事的
Medic! Medic!
救护!…
I wonder what "bitte,bitte" means.
你知道他在说什么吗?
What the hell are you wearing a life preserver for?
你穿着救生衣干嘛?
I can't swim.
我不会游泳
Normandy. It really is Normandy.
诺曼地,真的是诺曼地
This is madness,madness, sheer madness!
这真是疯了,疯了
What is it?
是什么?
I just talked to General Jodl, the F¨¹hrer is awake.
我刚和朱铎将军谈过 元帅醒了
I don't care if he's awake or not! What about the reserve panzers?
我不管他醒了没 后备装甲队呢?
The F¨¹hrer went into one of his tantrums...
元帅发怒了…
...and no one dared bring up the subject.
没人敢提任何事
They're still held in reserve!
部队还没出发
Yes,field marshal.
是的,战地元帅
Sir,if you would call the F¨¹hrer yourself...
长官,如果你要 亲自打电话给元帅的话…
...I am convinced he would respect your views.
我相信他会尊重你的看法
Call him?
要我打给他?
Call that Bohemian corporal?!
打电话给波西尼亚的下士?!
Crawl on my knees to him?!
要我去求他?
No! It is out of the question!
绝不可能
"Wounds my heart with a monotonous languor."
“用单调的沉闷伤害我的心”
What's that?
你在说什么?
Nothing,nothing of importance.
一切都不重要了
Here,let me help you.
这儿,我来帮你
You all right,Tom? Come on,they're up there.
你还好吗,汤姆? 快,他们在上面
-Sir. -Well?
-长官 -什么事?
Mr. Smith says to tell you he's stood his men too.
史密斯先生要转告你 他的部队已就绪
The Jerries are moving up into the woods...
德军正在将机枪和大炮…
...with machine guns and mortars.
搬进树林
-Tell the men to stand firm! -Tell the chaps--
-让他们随时待命! -话传下去…
Tell them to expect another counterattack,a heavy one.
告诉他们可能会受到严厉反击
-Here you are,mate. -Ta.
-拿去 -谢了
-What's the matter? -Listen.
-怎么了? -听着
I thought I heard bagpipes.
我想我听到了风笛声
Don't be daft!
少笨了
I told you I heard bagpipes! It's the reinforcements.
我真的听到了,是援兵来了
It's Lovat!
是洛维特特
Come on!
快一点
-Sorry I'm late. -Better than never,sir.
-对不起迟到了 -总比没来得好
Glad to see you,Shimmy.
真高兴见到你
You boys are right on target. What's the situation?
射的真准,情况如何?
Jerry's regrouping in the woods, about a mile.
德军在一里外重整
With mortars and machine guns.
有许多重型武器
Numbers?
数目呢?
No idea,Shimmy,but they seem to be moving forward in force.
我不知道有多少 不过好像在增强武力
In that case,we won't wait.
这样的话我们就不等了
We'd better get moving.
我们最好快点行动
All right,we're going across.
好,我们要穿过去
-Millin! -Sir?
-米伦! -长官?
"Black Bear," sir.
吹“黑熊”
All right,come on.
好,来吧
Everybody up!
每个人都起来!
On your feet!
站好!
There he goes. He's at it again.
风笛又在吹了
Ever hear such a bleeding racket in all your life?
你听过这么难听的声音吗?
Yeah,it takes an Irishman to play the pipes.
只有爱尔兰人才会吹风笛
Hold until relieved.
坚守到最后
North by east,north by east. Sainte-M¨¨re-Eglise is that way.
东北方,东北方 圣梅英格里斯在那个方向
Somebody turned that sign around.
有人移动过路标
Doesn't anybody in this outfit look at a compass besides me?
没人看一下罗盘吗?
Hey,you guys!
嘿,你们过来
Over here! Over here!
过来!…
Over here,on the double.
快点!
-Where you taking that? -We don't know,sir.
-你们要把车推去哪? -不知道
We took the wrong road.
我们迷路了
What do you got in here,ammo?
里面是什么,弹药吗?
Yes,sir.
是,长官
-You 82nd? -No,sir,101.
-你是82师的吗? -不,是101师
Well,you're in the 82nd now.
现在你是82师的了
-But,sir,we're-- -But what?
-可是长官… -可是什么?
Nothing,sir.
没事
All right,move out.
好,出发
-Knock that sign down! -Yes,sir.
-把路标拔掉 -是的,长官
-Something's moving up there,colonel. -Hit the dirt! Take cover.
-有人朝这儿来了,上校 -找掩蔽
Lieutenant Sheen,sir,A Company.
是A连的西恩少尉
Colonel,it's me!
上校,是我
-Where did you come from? -Sainte-M¨¨re-Eglise.
-你从哪来的? -圣梅英格里斯
We hold the main road and north side of the square.
我们守在圣梅英格里斯广场的北方
The Germans have a battery on the other side of the town...
从山头起到南边…
-...and command the countryside. -And Major Lance?
-整个地方都被德军占了 -兰斯上校呢?
-Holed up in a building in the square. -F Company?
-兰斯上校占据了一栋建筑物 -F连呢?
They overshot the drop zone and landed in the middle of the town.
F连越区降落在了那个镇上了
Go on.
继续说
It was a nightmare,sir. A slaughter.
真是场恶梦,是大屠杀
They were mowed down before they hit the ground.
他们在着陆前就遭到屠杀了
Major Lance sent me to try and contact you,sir.
兰斯上校派我来找你
He wants your permission to pull back and regroup outside of town.
他想撤退重新整备
No,damn it. We came here
不行,该死,我们是要来 占领圣梅英格里斯的
We're gonna take it and hold it.
我们要占领而且要坚守住
Follow the lieutenant,gentlemen.
跟着少尉,各位
-Sir. -Thank you.
-长官 -谢谢
British and Canadians advancing steadily from Sword,Gold,and Juno.
英军和加军在剑滩 黄金滩和朱诺滩稳定地推进
Anything from Omaha?
有奥玛哈来的消息吗?
Nothing since the first message: heavy fighting,heavy casualties.
除了第一次之后就没有了 “激战,伤亡惨重”
Sir.
长官
Omaha?
奥玛哈来的吗?
No.
不是
I can't understand why Jerry hasn't brought his heavy armor into play.
为什么德军还未全力反击呢?
All the panzer divisions except the 21 st...
除了21装甲师外…
...seem to be sitting it out in the rear.
其余的都在后方
Sir.
长官
"French commandos driving inland from Sword...
“法军从剑滩向内陆推进…
...have reached the outskirts of Ouistreham."
接近维斯特罕的外缘地带”
Ouistreham.
维斯特罕
Fall back!
撤退!
Take cover!
找掩护!
Tank support! We must have tank support!
坦克支援 我们必须要有坦克支援
Hello,Bastille. Hello,Batille. This is Windsor. Come on,Bastille!
呼叫巴斯地 这是温莎,请回答
Fire!
发射!
Attention!
立正!
Hello,Bastille. Hello,Batille. This is Windsor. Come on,Bastille!
呼叫巴斯地 这是温莎,请回答
I can't get them!
我联络不到他们
Keep trying! We must have support!
继续试,我们一定要有支援
Hold your positions. I'm going for a tank!
守住你的位置,我去找坦克来
Give us as much cover as you can!
尽可能给我们掩护
The bridge,right!
那座桥梁,右边
Fire!
开火!
Try for the cannon!
向加农炮开炮!
Get the wounded out of here!
把伤兵移开这儿!
Go back!
回去!
Get out of here!
快离开那儿!
You can't stay here!
你不能留在这
I am Mother Superior of the convent.
我是这儿的院长
The Sisters are qualified nurses.
这儿的修女都是合格护士
But madame-- I mean,Mother, we're in the middle of a battle!
可是,院长,我们现在… 我们还在打仗!
Excuse me. Take care of the wounded.
对不起,去照顾伤患
It's a tank!
是坦克车!
It's Kieffer!
是基佛!
In the other direction!
另外一边!
Clear away the debris! Hurry!
把碎片清干净!快点!
But where is the Luftwaffe?!
飞机在哪?
-I'm trying. -Yeah,yeah,you're trying.
-我正在试 -快点找到
The British troops have a beachhead here. They are moving inland.
英军已经登陆 正朝内陆推进
and have cut the highway.
美军守住了圣梅英格里斯 并切断了高速公路
We control this center section.
我们控制了中心地带
The Americans have landed but their attack has bogged down.
美军虽然登陆了 但却陷入苦战中
Rommel is right.
隆美尔说得对
If we can hold them on the beaches...
如果能把盟军挡在海滩上…
...the invasion will collapse.
侵略就会失败
Medic!
救护!
That thing still work?
无线电可以用吗?
Yes,sir,now and then.
是,时好时坏
-Anything from the other beaches? -Not directly.
-有从其它海滩来的消息吗? -没有直接的消息
A while ago the sergeant picked up some flashes from the destroyers.
但断断续续收到些 从驱逐舰上来的讯号
The 4th Division is off Utah Beach and moving inland.
第4师已离开犹他海滩 往内陆推进
Inland?
内陆?
-What about the 1 st Division? -They're hung up,sir.
-那第一师呢? -第一师像我们…
Like we are.
一样动弹不得
Move out.
出发
Medic!
救护!
-What do you think? -Think?
-你怎么看? -怎么看?
We must have close to 1000 casualties up to now.
我们大概死伤了一千人
Do you want me to have the ships start picking us up?
要联络船只来救援吗?
-You think it's that bad? -I don't see what else to do.
-你真的觉得很糟吗? -还有什么可以做的?
We can't get up this hill.
我们无法登上这座山
If we don't get off this beach, we won't have any division left.
要是留在这儿 就会全军覆没了
What?
什么?
These are our men,Tom.
这些是我们的弟兄,汤姆
You think we brought them in so some die and ask the rest to turn tail?
难道我们是带他们来这牺牲 再叫剩下的人逃命吗?
Hell,no. We're gonna get up that hill.
当然不是,我们不离开 我们要爬上去
Find me somebody to speak for the Rangers.
找人来跟突击队联络
Back down the beach on the right there's a gully.
往下潮海滩去是个小峡谷
With a heavily defended roadblock and machine gun nests on both sides.
还有固若金汤的路障
-If we can blow our way through-- -We've hit it three times.
-若我们能够突破… -我们试过三次了
-We didn't get close. -Three times isn't enough.
-根本无法靠近 -我知道,但三次还不够
We're gonna hit it again. Can you find me some engineers?
但我们要再试 可以找来一些可用的装备吗?
They're all around you!
四周都是
I mean engineers with equipment still working.
我是说找可用的装备来
Then I shouldn't radio the ships?
你不是要我联络船只吧?
No,damn it!
当然不是,该死的
We need bangalore torpedoes, bazookas,mortars,wire cutters...
我们需要破网雷、火箭筒 迫击炮…
...and every man that can stand. Pass the word,will you?
还有可以行动的士兵 把话传下去
Okay,Norm.
好,诺曼
Now listen to me,all of you.
大家都听我说
You guys got to snap out of it.
各位要打起精神
We're getting off of here, and we're going inland.
我们要往内陆前进了
What about weapons,general? My men lost everything.
武器怎么办? 弟兄们大多弄丢了所有装备了
They gotta have something to fight with.
他们不是懦夫,但也需要武器
Strip the dead and the wounded.
搜搜看死者和伤者的身上
Pick up anything that'll shoot.
把可用的武器找出来
I don't have to tell you the score, you all know it.
各位都知道…
Only two kinds of people are gonna stay on this beach:
这海滩上只有两种人会生存下来…
Those that are already dead and those that will die. Get off your butts!
已经死的和将要死的 大家打起精神
You guys are the fighting 29th!
你们都是骁勇善战的29师
I've looked at the naval reports.
我在看海军报告
Yes?
说什么?
According to reports from the offshore destroyers,Omaha is a shambles.
驱逐舰说,奥玛哈海滩尸横遍野
There's no evidence-- To quote the report exactly:
没有任何… 报告说…
"There is no evidence of any movement that can be observed off the beach."
“海滩上毫无生还迹象”
I'd better have a look through these.
我要研究一下这个报告
How is Ike taking it?
艾森豪反应如何?
Like everybody else,sir. Hanging on by his fingernails.
和每个人一样焦躁等待着
No,no! We must regroup according to Plan Six!
不,不,我们必须 根据计划六重新整备
Hello? Hello? Can you hear me?
喂,听得到吗?
I said we must regroup according to Plan Six.
我说,我们必须 根据计划六重新整备
Nonsense!
胡说!
If the panzers arrive,we still have time to use them.
若装甲队到了 它们还是可以被派上用场的
We'll drive to the coast!
我们开车去海滩
Shall we remove the files?
要把档案销毁吗?
I don't care! I want to get to the front at once,to Normandy!
我才不管,我要立刻 到前线去,去诺曼第
Yes,general.
是的,将军
-Where is everybody? -What?
-人都去哪了? -什么?
I said,where is everybody?
我是说,其他人呢?
I can't hear you.
我听不见
It's them bells.
是那些铃声
I've had them in my ears for 10 hours.
我已经听了十个小时了
Ding-dong,ding-dong.
叮当,叮当
Hey,sergeant,where's Major Lance?
兰斯上校在哪里?
We moved the CP to that building. The major's there.
我们把指挥中心移到那建筑物里 少校就在里面
Get him,the colonel's here.
去找他,上校来了
What?
什么?
Hold it!
停车!
Colonel,am I glad to see you!
上校,真高兴见到你
Those bodies. Get those bodies down.
尸体,把尸体搬下来
Why are you leaving them up there? Get them down!
怎么尸体还在上面?快搬下来
But we've been under fire,sir.
可是我们被炮火攻击
I know you have,but I don't care!
我知道,可是我不管
Get them down! Down!
去搬下来
-I don't want those boys left there. -Take a detail and cut them down.
-我不要弟兄们被挂在上面 -立刻将他们的名字记下,然后搬下来
-At once! -Yes,sir.
-立刻! -是的,长官
Has there been a linkup between our forces and the troops from the sea?
我军和海上来的军队会合了吗?
I don't know,major. I don't even know if the landings took place.
我连他们是否登陆了都不知道
But I am sure we're gonna hold this town until the linkup does come.
我只知道 我们要坚守住这直到会合为止
Whenever that is,today,tomorrow, till hell freezes over.
不管是什么时候,今天 明天,或是直到地狱冻结为止
For their sake, if for no other reason.
至少也是为了他们的缘故
Show me the enemy positions.
告诉我敌军位置
Well,sir,the Germans' strong point is right there.
德军的要塞就在这儿
That's over there on the hill. They've got no tanks yet.
在那座远山上,还没有坦克
They've got heavy guns and machine gun positions at the top of that road.
但有重型武器守住关口
How many men have you got?
你们有多少人?
Not enough.
不够
Lieutenant Wilson will take A Company and reinforce Major Lance.
威尔逊少尉会带A连 增援兰斯上校
The rest of the command will follow us straight up that road.
其余跟我们沿着路上去
Good luck,major.
祝你好运,少校
All right,A Company,fall out.
好,A连前进
-Private. -Yes,sir.
-二等兵 -是的,长官
It's a hell of a war.
真是惨烈
It's a privilege to serve with you,colonel.
能够跟你一起为国家效劳 是我的荣幸,上校
Well,God willing,we'll do what we came here to do.
奉天意旨 我们要完成到此的目的
Ready,sir.
好了,长官
Move out!
前进
The old man sure has changed since yesterday.
老家伙的确自昨天起就变了
Or maybe it's just that we've changed...
或许是从昨天起…
...since yesterday.
我们就变了
Lovat and his commandos have reached the bridge.
洛维特和他的部队到达了桥头
Bob,did you hear?
听到了吗?
Yes,I heard.
听到了
"Sainte-M¨¨re-Eglise captured by units of the 82nd Airborne."
圣梅英格里斯被82空降师占领
" 101 Airborne driving on Utah."
第101空降师往犹他海滩推进
That's good. Good.
很好…好
Yes,but if we can't get off Omaha it doesn't mean a damn. We know it.
是不错,但如果我们不能离开奥玛哈 就什么也别提了
We'll have two cut-off beachheads, one in British zone and one at Utah.
我们在占领了两个滩头 一个在英军区,一个在犹他海滩
Yes...
是…
...and the Germans in between.
当中夹着德军
You guys engineers?
你是工程师吗?
Yes,sir,299th.
是,我是第229连的
Where are your officers? Who's in charge here?
军官呢?这儿谁负责?
I guess I am,sir. None of our officers made it in.
我想是我 原来的军官阵亡了
What about your equipment? Those torpedoes work?
装备能用吗?
Yes,sir,we'll make them work!
我们一定会修复它的
-What's your name,sergeant? -It's Fuller,sir,John H.
-你叫什么名字,士官? -约翰富勒
You're Lieutenant Fuller from now on, whether you like it or not.
不管你喜不喜欢 现在开始你就是富勒少尉了
You send some men down to the foot of that gully with those torpedoes.
派些人到峡谷去 带着破网雷
-You and the rest of the men follow me. -Yes,sir!
-你和其他人跟我来 -是,长官
All right,men! Let's move that equipment down here.
把东西拿着,出发了
-I got a rifle,sir. -Well,good for you,son!
-我拿到把枪 -很好
The Rangers are ready,general.
部队准备好了,将军
Okay,major,move them out.
好,叫他们出发
Move them up!
出发
-Well,Tom? -We're ready.
-汤姆? -我们已经好了
As ready as we'll ever be.
准备好了吧
It'll work. It's got to work.
会成功的,一定会成功的
We're getting murdered here! We might as well move inland and get murdered!
不然会死在这儿 还不如死在前线
-You ready? -Yes,sir.
-准备好了吗,少尉? -是,长官
You're gonna blow that roadblock for me.
替我炸开路障
When I give the word everything pops at once. Okay?
听我命令 大家一起开始,懂吗?
Yes,sir.
遵命
First,we gotta blow a hole through that wire with bangalores.
首先要把铁网炸出一个洞来
If that works,we'll pack everything we've got into that wall.
然后到墙底下塞满炸弹
All right,let's go!
好,动作快
All right,let's go! Go! Go!
好,进攻了,快
We must leave. The main highway is under aerial attack.
该走了,主要道路开始遭到空袭
You don't say!
那还用说
Don't worry,Yank.
别担心,北佬
He's dead.
他死了
Give me a cigarette. I'm dying for a cigarette.
给我根烟,我哈死了
You hurt bad?
伤得重吗?
Shot down during the night.
我在夜间被射下来了
He was gonna make sure of me, but I got him...
他本来要杀我 但我先…
...with this.
杀了他
You ever killed a man? I mean,face to face?
你有面对面杀过人吗?
No.
没有
Neither had I,face to face.
我也没有试过面对面
I've been sitting here looking at him.
我坐着一直看他
Have you noticed anything peculiar about him?
发觉到他有什么 不一样的地方吗?
No.
没有
He's got his boots...
靴子…
...on the wrong feet.
穿反了
He must have been in a big hurry,huh?
他一定赶着上阵
Is it bad?
严重吗?
Split wide open...
从胯下到膝盖…
...from the crotch to the knee.
一路撕裂开来了
A medic came along and gave me a shot of morphine.
一个救护来给我打了吗啡
I hope he'll be back before it wears off.
希望药效过之前他会再回来
He said he would.
他说他会的
Did he sew you up?
他有替你缝吗?
Well,when he came ashore he lost most of his equipment.
他上岸时,几乎所有装备都丢了
So he pinned it together...
只有用安全针…
...with safety pins.
别起来了
Getting on toward night.
快入夜了
You know something?
你知道吗?
I haven't fired my gun all day.
我一天都没开过枪
I keep hearing shooting,but every time I get there,everybody's gone.
我听到子弹呼啸的声音 我每次都是在大家离开后到达的
Funny,isn't it?
奇怪吧?
He's dead.
他死了
I'm crippled.
我跛了
You're lost.
你迷失了
I suppose it's always like that.
我想永远都会是如此
I mean war.
我是说战争
I wonder who won.
不知道谁赢了
Okay,run me up the hill,son.
好,载我到山上
[ENGLISH]
[MANDARIN - R3] 字幕调整:十八公